Terence Beaujour. Jarvis Consulting

I graduated from Paris Diderot school with a Bsc in Science of Engineering, and I also have the equivalent of a Master in Data Science and Machine Learning Engineering that I got with Paris Sorbonne University and DataScientest. I started my career as a freelancer in algorithmic trading, and I used the MQL5 language to develop several bot for the MT5 platform. I have also worked on an arbitrage bot for the Binance exchange, using the Python language, with advanced concepts like asynchronous programming and multi threading. I have also worked one year as a software developer at Vezgo, a company specialized in crypto currency and DeFi, where my job was to implement and optimize several connector with NodeJS that connect to exchanges and blockchains in order to retrieve financial data and store them in a MongoDB database. We were using Agile methodology and beyond acquiring more advanced programming skills, I also learned how to manage a project, I improved my communication skills and I learned to work in a team. I am passionate by data science and data engineering and my goal is to join a great team of engineers so I can bring my skills and competences and I can learn as much as I can from them.

Skills

Proficient: Python, Linux/Bash, Machine Learning, Scikit Learn, Data analysis, Agile/Scrum, Git, Docker

Competent: NodeJS, RDBMS/SQL, Java, TensorFlow, PyTorch, MQL5, Linux/Bash, NoSQL

Familiar: C++, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, React, Kubernetes, AWS

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_TerenceBeaujour

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Implemented a software that retrieves and stores hardware information and resources usage for a Linux cluster of 10 nodes running on CentOS 7. Bash scripts were generated to store the data in a PostgreSQL database that was run by a docker container.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- JDBC App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- Grep App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not StartedSpark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

Highlighted Projects

Machine Learning [GitHub]: Implemented a complete machine/deep learning unit for the Nouméa hospital in New-Caledonia. This tool allows the hospital to answer different problems, Prediction of patient admission (classification), prediction of length of stay in the emergency department (regression) and prediction of patient flow the next day (Recurrent Neural Network).

Algorithmic Trading: Realization of an arbitrage algorithm for crypto currencies. Real time data retrieval with websockets on the Binance exchange, scanning of 1000 different triangles in real time, placing limit orders using multi-threading.

Professional Experiences

Software Engineer, Jarvis (2022-present): Worked on a complete project using Linux, SQL and docker, to help Jarvis team to monitor their cluster. Used Agile method to collaborate with other team members and to manage the project.

Software Developer, Vezgo (2021-2022): Optimized and implemented different connectors to connect and retrieve data from different exchanges and blockchain. Used NojeJS to implement the software, connected to MongoDB database to store and manage the data. Used git and github to manage the software and Agile method to manage the project.

Education

Paris-Sorbonne university (2021), Equivalent Master in France, Data SciencesParis Diderot school (2017-2018), Bsc Sciences of Engineering, Electrical Engineering

Miscellaneous

- Udacity Machine Learning (2019)
- Winner
- Trading (manual and algorithmic)
- Video game player
- Piano learner